One of your first tasks will be to classify a binary set of data;
第一个任务是对一组二元数据进行分类
images taken during the day or night.
即白天或晚上拍摄的照片
But before you can complete this task,
在完成此任务之前
you first have to learn about how images are seen by machines.
首先需要学习计算机是如何查看图像的
Let's take this image of a car.
我们来看看这个汽车图像
This is actually a self-driving car on the road.
实际上是一个在路上行驶的无人驾驶汽车
And look at how a computer understands it.
看看计算机是如何理解该图像的
We'll be working with a grayscale image like this first,
我们首先将处理像这样的黑白图像
because color adds another layer of complexity,
因为颜色会额外带来复杂性
but the same general principles will apply as we'll see soon.
但是遵守相同的一般原则 稍后我们就会发现
So, when I show you this image,
当我向你展示这个图像时
you might say, "Oh, it's a picture of a car."
你可能会说“噢 是一张汽车照片”
And it is, but it's also a 2D grid of values,
没错 并且还是二维网格值
also known as an array with some width and height.
亦称之为具有宽度和高度的数组
Let me show you what I mean.
我来解释下
This and all digital images,
这种图和所有数字图像
are all made of a grid of pixels,
都由像素网格组成
which are very small units of a single color or intensity.
即单个颜色强度的很小单位
And if we zoom in on the image of the car like this area around the wheel,
如果我们放大车轮的这个区域
we can get a better look at these pixels.
可以更清晰地看到这些像素
Now you can see it's really starting to look more like a grid.
现在可以看出像一个网格
Each pixel color in this grid,
这个网格中的每个像素颜色
has a corresponding numerical value.
都有一个对应的数值
For grayscale images like this,
对于这样的灰度图像
the value of each pixel ranges from zero to 255.
每个像素的值范围是从 0 到 255
Zero is black, 255 is white,
0 表示黑色 255 表示白色
and grey is anywhere in between.
所有中间值表示灰色
So, a value of around 120 is a medium grey,
因此 120 左右的值表示
in between black and white.
介于黑色和白色之间的中灰色
And a value of around 20,
20 左右的值
will be a very very dark grey, close to black.
表示非常非常暗的灰色 接近黑色
And each of these pixels,
每个像素
in addition to having a color value,
除了具有颜色值之外
also has a location xy in this image grid.
在这个图像网格中还具有位置 (x,y)
These axes are a lot like axes for a graph,
这些坐标轴和图形中的坐标轴很像
only for digital images,
但是对于数字图像来说
the top left coordinate is at the origin or the point x equals zero, y equals zero.
左上角的坐标是原点 即 x=0 y=0 的点
Now, our image of a car is 427 pixels in height and 640 in width.
这个汽车图像的高为 427 像素 宽为 640 像素
And the pixel locations are on a grid that starts at index zero.
像素位置位于从索引 0 开始的网格上
From zero to 369 columns,
列从 0 到 369
and from zero to 426 rows.
行从 0 到 426
As an example, at the location x equals 190 and y equals 375,
例如 在 x = 190 y = 375 的位置
we have a pixel on this wheel at the bottom left of the image.
是图像左下角车轮上的一个像素
The pixel value is 28,
像素值为 28
a dark dark grey.
表示深灰色
And you might ask how I know this.
你可能会疑问 我是如何知道的
Well, in code we can actually find any single pixel value by location.
在代码中 我们可以通过位置知道任何一个像素值
So let's do that. We'll read in our image of a car,
我们来试一下 我们将读取这个汽车图像
but first, I'll import the libraries I need.
首先 我将导入所需的库
This includes matplotlib.image, which let's us read in any image.
包括 matplotlib.image 该库使我们能够读取任何图像
You'll also see cv2,
还导入了 cv2
which is a computer vision library and you'll learn more about that soon.
它是一个计算机视觉库 稍后你将深入学习该库
I'll also be using matplotlib qt,
我还将使用 matplotlib qt
qt makes us image pop up in an interactive window when I display it.
当我显示图像时 qt 使图像能够在交互式窗口中弹出
So I'll read in the image of a car,
我将使用 matplotlib 的 imread 函数
using matplotlib's imread function.
读取汽车图像
And I'll pass in the name of our image file.
传入图像文件的名称
I have the image of a car and in images directory in the same location as this notebook.
这个汽车图像位于 images 目录中 和这个 notebook 的位置一样
Next, I'll actually print out some information about this image.
接着我将输出关于该图像的一些信息
I want to print out its dimensions by referencing image.shape.
我将通过引用 image.shape 输出图像大小
Now we can see its height and width in pixels.
现在可以看到以像素为单位的高度和宽度了
And we see another value three,
并且看到了另一个值 3
which corresponds to the number of color channels this images has.
对应的是这个图像的颜色通道数量
And we'll learn more about this value soon.
稍后我们将详细了解这个值
For now, we'll convert our image to be grayscale.
暂时将该图像转换为灰度图像
And I'll convert it to grayscale using a computer vision library.
为此 我们将使用计算机视觉库
For now, know that this has built-in color conversion code,
暂时只需记住该库具有内置的颜色转换代码
like changing an image from red-green-blue color to grayscale.
例如将图像从红绿蓝颜色转换为灰度图像
Then I'll display this grayscale image.
然后显示这个灰度图像
This opens our interactive window.
这样就打开了交互式窗口
And as I pass over this image with my mouse,
当我在这个图像中移动光标时
you can see the xy location displayed on the bottom left of the screen,
可以看到屏幕左下角显示了 x y 的位置
as well as the corresponding pixel value.
以及对应的像素值
Down here by the wheel,
在下面的车轮部分
we have dark pixel values, around 28, 29.
显示了在 28 和 29 左右的深色像素值
And up here in the sky, we have some light pixel values.
天空部分对应的是一些浅色像素值
You can see around 220 or even higher.
可以看到 220 左右或甚至更高的像素值
And if we go back to our notebook,
回到 notebook
we can print out the value of a single pixel by accessing it by location.
可以通过位置访问单个像素并输出像素值
I'll say x equals 190 and y equals 375.
假设 say x = 190 y = 375
And I can access that pixel value by looking at that location in our great image y, x.
我可以通过在灰度图像中查看该位置访问该像素值 即 (y,x)
Finally, I'll print out that value and we can see that it's 28.
最后 我将输出该值 可以看出是 28
Every pixel in an image is just a numerical value.
图像中的每个像素都是一个数值
And we can also change these pixel values.
我们还可以更改这些像素值
We can multiply every single one by a scalar to change how bright the image is.
我们可以通过使每个像素乘以一个标量 更改图像的亮度
We can shift each pixel value to the right or left and many more operations.
我们可以将每个像素向右或向左移动 还可以执行更多其他操作
Treating images as grids of numbers is the basis for many image processing techniques.
将图像当做数字网格是很多图像处理技术的基础
Most color and shape transformations are done just by mathematically operating on image,
很多颜色和形状转换就是通过对图像进行数学处理
and changing it pixel by pixel.
并逐个更改像素实现的